# **Derrick Johnson**

910-880-9175 // dj51234@yahoo.com // djdeveloper.me

FRONT END DEVELOPER with a seven-year history of professional experience working with small clients as well as bigger companies such as American Express. I began working with design-only projects in my free time but eventually transitioned to the wonderful world of web development. I took a short break from coding to explore Network Security and virtual machines in the military but I have returned to my true passion; coding! I have solid working knowledge of HTML, CSS, Javascript and Python. I also have basic knowledge of Django and the fundamentals of getting an application deployed and running. I am knowledgeable of each phase involved in the web development project cycle such as: working with customer experience, designers, back end developers and fellow front end developers to complete tasks.

#### SKILLS:

• HTML5 CSS3 SASS JavaScript jQuery NPM/Node Webpack Gulp Wordpress Photoshop OOP/BEM Information Security Vue Python Django React

#### **CREDENTIALS:**

- Bachelors of Science in Criminal Law (Minor in Forensics) East Carolina University // 2009-2012
- COMPTIA Security + // 2017
- Military Network + // 2020

## **EXPERIENCE:**

## ISSO/HELP DESK LEAD // Marine Corps // August 2017 - December 2020

- Maintained and enforced IA standards and cybersecurity procedures within unit of 400+ individuals.
- Helped identify possible network vulnerabilities within unit and consulted with Information Security Systems Manager (ISSM) for solutions.
- Daily tasks include working in Active Directory creating user accounts, email accounts and trouble shooting common user errors within a virtual environment.
- Utilized BMC Remedy trouble ticket application to identify and solve IT issues within the unit.

# FRONT END DEVELOPER // Red Ventures // August 2016 - January 2017

- Tested front-end code in multiple browsers to ensure cross-browser compatability.
- Developed functional prototypes for clients to ensure quality control before project development phase.
- Developed several versions of web pages with different functionality, components or advertisement text to leverage split testing..

#### CREATIVE DEVELOPER // Investor Management Services // December 2015 - August 2016

- Developed and managed websites for financial company using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery and Wordpress.
- Oversaw all design and development phases of website development of client websites.
- Gained experience working in an agile/waterfall/JIRA structure and created HTML email templates and newsletters for email marketing campaigns.

## WEB DEVELOPER // Linium // December 2015 - August 2016

- Developed and designed client websites using Photoshop, HTML5 and CSS.
- Converted PSDs into hand-coded HTML/CSS.
- Designed wireframes and functional web prototypes using front end development tools.

## IT Specialist // Army National Guard // January 2009 - January 2015

• Assisted with every day IT operations involving setup of military technologies, computers and other communications.